[roaring]
[narrator] Strange beasts
and monsters.
Vast riches.
Hidden treasures.
Evil haunts.
Uncharted frontiers.
The mysterious unknown.
The people who are captivated
by the magic in those words…
are called…
Hunters.
[theme song playing]
I... give up!
-What?
[Leorio] Bastard!
I knew we shouldn’t have trusted you!
All you’re good for
is sabotaging the other applicants.
You’re just a worthless piece of garbage!
It took you long enough.
That’s what I do every year.
And I’ll keep on doin’ it
for as long as I can.
I don’t care
about passing the Hunter Exam;
I’m in it for the thrills.
BEWARE x OF x PRISONERS
[narrator] The Third Phase of the Exam
is underway at Trick Tower,
where long-term prisoners are held.
Gon and friends have chosen to partake
in a five-on-five battle
with some of the inmates.
Thanks to Tonpa,
they’ve already suffered their first loss.
The next round
will pit Gon against Sedokan.
Who knows what the upcoming battle
will bring?
Now, then.
SEDOKAN
149-YEAR SENTENCE, SERIAL BOMBINGS
As you’ve all probably noticed,
I’m not terribly strong.
I don’t enjoy fighting, or running,
jumping, anything physical, really.
[Gon] I like that stuff a lot more
than thinking.
I guess I’ve never really been
all that great at using my head.
[Sedokan] I thought so.
So, I came up with a game.
One I think we’ll both enjoy.
-A game?
-[Sedokan] Yes.
Yes. A simple game that doesn’t rely
on mental or physical activity.
What is it?
[Sedokan chuckles]
We each light a candle at the same time
and whoever’s candle goes out first
is the loser.
All right?
Yep. Makes sense to me.
I’m in; let’s do it!
[Sedokan] Okay. In that case…
So which candle do you want to use?
It’s your choice.
Press ‘O’ for the long candle
or press ‘X’ if you would rather have
the short one.
Choose by majority rule.
So, we have to choose one?
This is a damn trap!
Normally, you’d want to go
for the long one.
Which means that low-life
must’ve done something to sabotage it!
[Kurapika]
Yes. That would be the safe assumption.
However, it could be a trick
and he’s actually tampered
with the short one.
Hey, you’re right.
So, when you put it that way…
Correct. There is no end.
Sounds like you’ve got yourselves
a real dilemma.
You keep your big mouth shut!
Yeah, yeah.
Something happens when you’re presented
with an obviously biased choice:
suspicion mounts and
the decision-making process seizes up.
Yes. This truly is a dilemma.
Moreover,
the psychological impact
of making the wrong choice
is much greater than if the option
was between two evenly matched options.
[grumbles]
[smug chuckle]
[Sedokan] All right, then…
Please, take all the time you need.
It’s a majority decision
but feel free to talk about it first.
No rush. We have plenty of time,
believe me.
Hey! What should I pick?
Dammit.
Good question.
[chuckles]
Gon! The choice is up to you!
Pick whichever candle you think is best
is the best option.
That’s how we’ll all vote.
Are you sure about this?
It’s just that
he doesn’t think things through.
Instead of fretting over the choice,
let’s just put our faith
in Gon’s instincts.
Trust his instincts, huh?
Oh, I get to choose?
In that case
I’ll go with the long candle, okay?
[smirks]
You want the long one?
Are you sure about that?
Of course! The longer the candle,
the longer it burns.
It’s kind of a no-brainer.
Well, that’s one way to look at it.
I told you he wasn’t gonna
think it through.
Well. That settles it.
[beep]
Yeah, it’s not like
we’d be able to figure out
which one’s the trap, anyway.
[beep]
-[smirks]
-[beep]
[Sedokan] Okay!
Looks like you get the long candle
and I’ll take the short one.
[metal grinding]
All right. Let’s light ‘em together.
[chuckles]
[chuckling]
[Killua] So, uh...
Normally how long
would it take that candle to burn?
I would estimate five to six hours.
[strong wind blowing]
Oh, wow.
That sure was a close one.
[wind blows]
[Leorio] There’s a pretty strong wind
coming up from below.
They’ll have to stay still
and keep an eye on those flames.
There’s no chance
to let their guards down.
If you don’t pay attention
your candle will blow out.
[Gon] Yeah, I know.
That’s because you’re planning
to do something bad.
Aren’t you?
Otherwise, your short candle
would go out first.
I won't do anything.
‘Cause, you see...
I came prepared.
[startled cry]
[smirks] There. See?
Hey. Take a look at Gon’s candle.
The flame suddenly got a lot stronger!
I should’ve known.
He somehow laced Gon’s candle
with gunpowder or some other accelerant.
That’s why it’s burning so much faster!
[Gon] Ow! Hot!
-[Killua] At this rate...
-[Gon] Hot...
[Killua] ...he’s only got another
two or three minutes!
[Leorio] Damn!
Hey! That was a dirty trick!
I knew it! You messed with the long one,
didn’t you?
[smirks] You’re wrong.
I had four candles prepped and ready.
The disparate choice I presented you with
was merely camouflage
for the actual trap!
You assumed that one of the two
would be a trick candle.
The choices were so uneven
you never stopped
to consider the possibility
that I’d rigged both of them.
In the end it didn’t really matter
which of the candles you picked.
Long or short…
I’d have handed you
an oil-soaked candle either way.
I guess now that the flame is
burning so much stronger…
it’ll take a lot more
than a little breeze to put it out.
Hm?
He's fast!
[chuckles]
I win!
Yes!
[solemn grunt]
[Lippo] Ooh.
That one’s got a real spring
in his step, doesn’t he?
And he knows how to take advantage
of a bad situation.
Impressive. Very impressive.
[Gon] All right! I won!
You sure as hell did!
That’s one win for us!
Once Kurapika and I win, we can advance!
Idiot. That’s what you get
for relying on cheap tricks.
Damn.
[hooded prisoner] Proper deception
calls for a little sacrifice.
Watch and learn.
[loud clatter]
All right.
I’ll take the next one.
[roaring]
HUNTER GLOSSARY
LIPPO
[prisoner cackling]
The next contender’s gotta face me!
MAJITANI
108-YEAR SENTENCE
MULTIPLE CRIMES,
INCLUDING FRAUD AND BLACKMAIL
Man, that is one freaky body.
Yeah. And face.
Do ya see this, kid?
I’ve killed nineteen people so far.
But it’s such an uneven number.
To tell the truth, it kinda bugs me.
[snickering]
I’ve been lookin’ forward
to meeting number twenty for a while.
[evil laughter]
Oh, great.
We’re dealing with a serial killer?
[Majitani] The only way I’ll do this is
if we put our lives on the line.
It’s all or nothin’, do ya hear me, brat?
Gimme blood!
Spilling entrails!
And sweet agony!
[roaring in laughter]
Oh yeah.
You must be terrified right now.
[Kurapika] Very well.
[Majitani] Huh?
You can decide how we settle this.
And I will accept it.
[Majitani chuckles]
You’ve got some balls, kid!
[scoffs]
But I know you’re quaking in your boots.
How long can you keep up
the tough guy act?
Then you’re accepting a death match.
We go until one of us
either dies or admits defeat,
and not a second earlier, understand?
However…
Don’t think admitting defeat or surrender
will stop me.
Never has and, in fact, it never will,
so get it out of your head right now.
[maniacal laughter]
Well?
Scared stiff now, aren’t ya?
[Kurapika] Fine. I accept.
Huh?
Shall we begin?
[Majitani] What is he, an idiot?
Didn’t he hear what I just said?
This is the real deal.
We’re fighting to the death!
Wait, he should be trembling
just at the sight of me!
Hold on! There’s something
I forgot to mention.
Absolutely no weapons are allowed.
So, this has to be a simple fistfight.
Even though I’ve been hired
as an Examiner,
I am still a prisoner.
And that means
that I’m not allowed to carry weapons.
That makes sense.
I understand.
It there anything else you forgot?
If not, I’d like to get started.
[Majitani grunts]
That little bastard!
He had a concealed weapon.
I’m glad I said something
before it was too late.
But from the look of it,
he doesn’t rely on it much.
Is he really that confident
in his combat skills?
No. I don’t think its that’s it, either.
[derisive snort]
I bet he’s dying to run away
but he doesn’t want to look like a coward
in front of his friends.
Or maybe he’s just so stupid
that he doesn’t comprehend how scary I am!
He can’t even wrap his head around it!
Yeah! Yeah, yeah, that’s gotta be it!
[sinister grin]
Well, in that case,
I’ve got a few cards up my sleeve
for dealing with fools like him.
[inhales deeply, grunts]
[flexing and grunting]
Hey, guys. Is Kurapika gonna be okay?
‘Cause if you ask me,
this guy looks pretty dangerous.
[Killua]
What looks so dangerous about him?
It’s obvious, well, to me, anyway,
that this guy’s a big talker.
He doesn’t have the guts to hit anybody,
let alone kill them.
-[Gon] I wouldn’t worry about it much.
-Huh?
Why not?
Because when I’m looking at him,
I don’t get chills or anything.
What does that mean?
I think it’s time
to show you my secret weapon!
[roars]
The first of many!
Here he comes!
[roaring]
[Kurapika grunts]
Oh, my God.
He just punched a hole in the damn floor!
[Majitani] That was perfect.
And that’s not the only trick
up my sleeve.
[smirks]
[gasps]
Look at his tattoo;
it’s a spider with twelve legs!
And that means...
Yeah. I recognize it.
Anybody who wants to be a Hunter
has heard all about tattoos like that one.
It’s the symbol worn by members
of that nefarious band of vicious thieves,
the Phantom Troupe!
Really?
Yeah. No doubt about it.
Its meaning is widely known.
In fact, I-- I heard about them
straight from Kurapika.
[Majitani] Between the steel implants
that gives me the strength
to shatter rock with my bare hands
and the symbol of the Phantom Troupe...
they make one hell of a combo.
Nobody would want to fight me
after getting a peek at those!
[Majitani laughing]
[Majitani] Aw, what’s wrong?
Cat got your tongue?
Name’s Majitani!
I’m one of the Phantom Troupe’s
four devas!
That first strike
was just an introduction.
This is your last chance to give up.
If you do, I’m still willing to...
Huh?
[seething breathing]
Hey... What’s wrong with you?
What are you...
Huh?
[grunts]
[Majitani groaning]
[strangled cries]
[Majitani] Wait! Wait, I get it!
Hold on, wait! Please don’t!
You win, okay?
[whistles]
[Kurapika] Take this to heart.
First,
a genuine Phantom Troupe tattoo
has the member’s number
inscribed on the spider’s back.
Second,
they don’t bother tallying the people
they’ve killed
because it’s irrelevant to them.
And third,
don’t ever mention the Phantom Troupe
to me again.
If you do...
I will kill you with my bare hands.
Oh, wow…
Kurapika...
Yeah. I saw that one
coming from a mile away.
[Leorio] Hey, are you okay?
[Kurapika] Yes. I’m not injured.
[Leorio] No, I mean,
is it safe for us
to be around you right now?
[Kurapika]
From the first moment I saw him,
I knew he wasn’t nearly
as powerful as he looked.
And in my mind,
I knew right from the start
that the tattoo was a fake.
But as soon as I saw that spider,
my vision went almost completely red.
Well, nobody’s gonna blame you for that.
[Kurapika] To be perfectly honest…
-Huh?
Whenever I see a spider, any spider,
all my rationale collapses
and I turn primal.
You should've told us.
Like, a long time ago.
[Kurapika] That can only mean one thing.
The rage inside me
remains as strong as ever.
I suppose...
I should be happy.
I think we ought to keep Kurapika
away from any spiders, from now on.
Oh yeah.
[Bendot] Damn you, Majitani.
You were completely worthless out there.
Those facial scars on him
are from a botched plastic surgery.
That’s one hell of a fraud he pulled off.
Okay. You know what’s happening, right?
After two losses, it’s do or die.
[hooded woman] I’ll handle it.
In fact, I know just the thing.
All right!
Time for me to secure our victory!
[narrator]
With Kurapika’s triumph over Majitani,
they only need one more win
to clear the trial
and reach the next Phase.
But the question on all of their minds
is how will Leorio
handle the next challenge?
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Next time:
Trick To The Trick!
The trick to the trick is to trick...
I can't say it.
[Killua] Say it properly!